- imohammed12@student.go vst.edu
- 3127099174
- CHICAGO, United States
- in linkedin.com/in/mohammed imran14
- github.com/14imran





Big Data

Web Development

Machine Learning

DevOps



Sulfuric

- Sulfuric is a product that helps freelancers manage their projects/clients/payments/invoices /proposals/contracts. Built end to end in MERN Stack.
- ・ Link 🛂

Imran Mohammed

Pursuing Masters in Computer Science

Full Stack Developer with experience in all fields of web development from the designing and building Service APIs, User Interfaces, and deploying the application to cloud platforms. Worked on building progressive web applications. I spend a lot of time researching and learning niche technologies. Expert in diverse programming languages, including JavaScript and Java.



WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER GLASCO TECHNOLOGIES

05/2021 - 12/2021

SERVICE BASED COMPANY .WORKED FOR CLIENTS FROM CANADA AND USA

PREDICTIVE MARKETING INTELLIGENCE APPLICATION

- Increased customer base by 24% following a series of dedicated sales campaigns.
 Tech stack React Js, MongoDb, Node Js, Express
- Integrated Twilio for managing messaging campaigns and Maligun for sending bulk emails
- Included simple and interactive React charts to visualize the analyzed data
- Department Of Revenue Application
- Leveraged React JS resources for all data access, encapsulating URL's and standardizing data access interfaces. Maintaining Parent and Child component's state by using Redux Js.
- I was responsible for creating RESTFUL Web Services using Node.js & MySql
- Used SQL Server Management Studio and Heidi SQl to manage the backend data that was deployed on Clear Db
- Created CI/CD Pipelines to automate the build, deploy, test and monitoring process

DEVELOPER CONSULTANT

ARCALIS.IO

01/2021 - 04/2021

Newcastle UK

- GENIUS COMMUNICATION APP
- Developed a communication app in 8 weeks and deployed it to AWS cloud platform
- Tech Stack Reactis Reduxis Mongodb Node Js Express



EDUCATION

 GOVERNORS STATE UNIVERSITY MASTERS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

01/2022 - Present

CHICAGO, USA



Droad

- Your daily news app is a product that enables users to read news articles and write blogs simultaneously. Implemented features that improves overall user experience.
- Link ☑

Follow Open Source Users

- This product helps users follow open source contributors. Users can view the contributor's list and click on the follow button to follow the contributors.
- Link ☑

EDUCATION

JAWAHARLAL NEHRU TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY HYDERBAD, INDIA

09/2020

BACHELORS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

- My Major project in engineering was building a Social networking website for developers that is a JavaScriptbased project which allows developers to communicate, share ideas, activities, events in the network.
- This system focuses on online communication. Allows the users to promote social responsibilities like development best practices, Startup environment, funding, blogs on building applications that are useful for the viewers.

IRONHACK MADRID, EUROPE

11/2020 - 09/2020

9 week intensive web development boot camp

- Front end technologies mastered: HTML | CSS | Javascript ES6 | React Back end technologies learned: ExpressJs | NodeJs | MongoDb |
- Version Control: Git | Github
- Back end technologies mastered: ExpressJs | NodeJs | MongoDb | Axios